Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff meeting minutes, 1927-1938, 1951-1952 and undated RL.00749
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff meeting minutes
1927-1938, 1951-1952 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00749
8.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Collection consists chiefly of verbatim minutes of a variety of staff meetings held at the New York and Chicago offices of JWT. Also included are advertisements, photographs, articles, and other printed material attached to minutes as background material or supplemental reading for the meetings. A set of subject indexes are included for some of the meeting series. Topics discussed include account histories, case studies and company profiles; activities of international and domestic JWT offices including country profiles; advertising and client relations during a depression; development and use of advertising media (film, outdoor, print, radio, television); general business and economic conditions; market research; new business activity; promotional techniques (coupons, merchandising, retail store displays); the structure and function of various JWT departments; and social trends. Companies frequently mentioned include Andrew Jergens, Cutex, General Motors, J.C. Penney, Johns-Manville, Lever Brothers, Kraft, Pennsylvania Railroad, and Standard Brands. Speakers include Alfred Harcourt, Arno Johnson, Clarence Darrow, Claude Hooper, Daniel Starch, Edward Steichen, Fanny Bell, John B. Watson, John U. Reber, Kennett Hinks, Margaret Bourke-White, Paul T. Cherington, Rudy Vallee, Ruth Waldo, Sam Meek, Stanley Resor, Will Hays, and William Esty. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Access to the originals is restricted. Photocopies are available for general use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff meeting minutes were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Restricted Materials (Originals); Use Copies.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York.
Collection Overview
Collection consists chiefly of verbatim minutes of a variety of staff meetings held at the New York and Chicago offices of JWT. Also included are advertisements, photographs, articles, and other printed material attached to minutes as background material or supplemental reading for the meetings. A set of subject indexes are included for some of the meeting series. Topics discussed include account histories, case studies and company profiles; activities of international and domestic JWT offices including country profiles; advertising and client relations during a depression; development and use of advertising media (film, outdoor, print, radio, television); general business and economic conditions; market research; new business activity; promotional techniques (coupons, merchandising, retail store displays); the structure and function of various JWT departments; and social trends. Companies frequently mentioned include Andrew Jergens, Cutex, General Motors, J.C. Penney, Johns-Manville, Lever Brothers, Kraft, Pennsylvania Railroad, and Standard Brands. Speakers include Alfred Harcourt, Arno Johnson, Clarence Darrow, Claude Hooper, Daniel Starch, Edward Steichen, Fanny Bell, John B. Watson, John U. Reber, Kennett Hinks, Margaret Bourke-White, Paul T. Cherington, Rudy Vallee, Ruth Waldo, Sam Meek, Stanley Resor, Will Hays, and William Esty.
Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Minutes; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; Andrew Jergens Company (Cincinnati, Ohio); General Motors Corporation; Johns-Manville Corporation; Lever Brothers Company; Kraft Foods Company; Pennsylvania Railroad; Standard Brands Incorporated; Johnson, Arno H. (Arno Hallock), 1901-; Daniel Starch and Staff; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973; Hinks, Kennett Webb, 1897-1982; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Waldo, Ruth; Meek, Samuel W. (Samuel Williams), 1895-; Resor, Stanley Burnet, 1879-1962
- Restricted Materials (Originals), 1927-1938, 1951-1952 and undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Original meeting minutes for the Account Representative Meetings, Creative Organization Meetings, JWT Forum Meetings, Monday Evening Staff Meetings, and Men's and Women's Apprentice Group Meetings.
  - Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1927, January 11-1928, August 29) (Box 1)
  - Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1928 September 12-1929 April 17) (Box 1a)
  - Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1929, May 1-1930, August 26) (Box 2)
  - Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1930, September 9 -1931, May 26) (Box 3)
  - Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1931, June 2-1932, February 16); Index 1927-1932 (Box 4)
  - Creative Organization Meeting Minutes (1932, March 5-1933, March 29) (Box 5)
  - Creative Organization Meeting Minutes (1933, April 12-1934, October 11); Indices (Box 6)
  - JWT Forum Meeting Minutes (1936, January 7-1938, October 25) (Box 7)
  - Monday Evening Staff Meeting Minutes (1930, March 3-May 26) (Box 8)
  - Monday Evening Staff Meeting Minutes Index by subject and speaker, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Men and Women Apprentice Group Meetings (1936, September 3-1938, October 7) (Box 8)
  - Chicago Office Junior Forum, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
- Use Copies, 1927-1938, 1951-1952 and undated; 1
  - Minutes of Representatives' Meetings, 1927-1932; 1
    Scope and Contents
    Representatives' Meetings, attended by top company executives and account representatives, were held weekly from 1927 until 1932 to discuss the state of the company. Subjects included clients, advertising practices, company finances, activities of international and domestic offices and branches, and general business conditions. Meetings often featured a talk on a specific topic by a staff member. [Source: Accession record.]
    - 1927 Apr. 19 (Box 1)
      New business; Curtis; N. W. Ayer; Lux; Procter & Gamble; Camay; John U. Reber; John B. Watson; Paul Cherington; William C. Esty
    - 1927 Apr. 26 (Box 1)
      Standard Oil; Corning Glass Company; Certo; Lux; Hellmann's; Simmons; Pennsylvania Railroad; Maxwell House; Fleischmann; JWT newsletter; Stanley B. Resor; Samuel Yellin; Stewart L. Mims; Henry C. Fowler
    - 1927 May 3 (Box 1)
      Boston Evening American; Lux; Pennsylvania Railroad; Meredith Publications; Postum; Campbell's Soup; Shredded Wheat; Curtis; new business; prospective clients; newsletter; Mr. Ricketts
    - 1927 May 10 (Box 1)
      Newsletter; chain store business; California Crushed Fruits Company; Deering Milliken Company; Schumaker; Standard Oil; Ford; business trends; Art Department
    - 1927 May 17 (Box 1)
      "The Curve of Progress"; retail shopping areas; sales analysis; Paul Cherington
    - 1927 May 24 (Box 1)
      Art Department; Colman's Mustard "Mustard Club"; Fleischmann's; Sloan's Liniment; General Motors; European offices; London Office; Arthur Hartzell (Spain); Clement Watson (Berlin)
    - 1927 May 31 (Box 1)
      New business; Du Pont; Vick's Vaporub; United Fruit Company; "Talk on Hellman's Blue Ribbon Mayonnaise"; Lloyd Baillie
    - 1927 June 7 (Box 1)
      New business; Gotham Hosiery Company; Robeson Rochester; Brillo; U.S. Rubber Keds; Yale Electric Corporation; DuPont; Eveready; Woman's Home Companion; Ladies' Home Journal; Good Housekeeping; "Changing Trade Names"; Paul Cherington sales analysis; Earle Clark on preparation charges
    - 1927 June 14 (Box 1)
      New business; Campfire Marshmallow; J. C. Penney Company; Nestle Circuline Wave; Curtis Brothers; Michigan Lumber Manufacturing
    - 1927 June 21 (Box 1)
      New business; Pennsylvania Rubber; Illinois Merchants Trust Company; J. C. Penney; Curtis; DuPont; Lux Toilet Soap; John Reber; William Esty on Lux; advertising photography; Paul Cherington on business trends in oil, steel, and building industries
    - 1927 June 28 (Box 1)
      New business; DuPont; Campfire Marshmallow; J.C. Penney; United Fruit; Standard Oil; Ethyl Gas; General Motors; Pennsylvania Rubber; Gruen; William Day on JWT advertising campaign costs; print advertising circulation and costs; News Bulletin
    - 1927 July 7 (Box 1)
      Baltimore Census of Distribution; Pond's; Fleischmann; News Bulletin; General Motors; Cheek Neal Coffee Company; Pennsylvania Rubber; Maxwell House; Henry Miner (Egypt); John Reber; Gilbert Kinney; Stewart L. Mims; Lloyd Baillie; print advertising placement
    - 1927 July 12 (Box 1)
      News Bulletin; Scott Paper; Campbell's Soup; J.C. Penney; Nestle; Fox Films; Equitable; chain stores; grocery stores; manufacturing; Paul Cherington on chain stores
    - 1927 July 19 (Box 1)
      Newspaper advertising (position; insertions; schedules); Fleischmann; Pond's; Lux Toilet Soap
    - 1927 July 26 (Box 1)
      Scott Paper; J.C. Penney; DuPont; National Radiator; Nestle; Standard Oil; Meredith Publications; Farm Advertising; "Better Homes and Gardens;" "Dairy Farmer"; Vogue; Successful Farming; farm publications
    - 1927 Aug. 2 (Box 1)
      Welch Grape Juice; Welch-Ade; outdoor advertising; Nashville
    - 1927 Aug. 9 (Box 1)
      Campfire Marshmallow; Gillette; Karagheusian; DuPont; cigarette and tobacco advertising; Liggett & Myers; Blackstone; Old Gold; Campbell Soup; Morse & Rogers Shoe; Hartford Advertising Club; Fleischmann baking and sales research; advertising research investigations; cosmetic market research; newspaper advertising; Pond's market research; sales of foil; mail investigation
    - 1927 Aug. 16 (Box 1)
      U. S. Rubber Keds; Pennsylvania Railroad; Stewart Mims; department and chain stores; Art Department; poster advertising; magazine advertising; consumer psychology
    - 1927 Aug. 23 (Box 1)
      Quorum not met; meeting cancelled.
    - 1927 Aug. 30 (Box 1)
      Newspaper advertising; Fleischmann; Rinso; Lever Brothers; Scott Paper; Lux Toilet Soap; Franklin Baker; survey research
    - 1927 Sept. 8 (Box 1)
      New business; Squibbs perfume; Bovril; Norwich shaving cream; Pinaud; Pond's in England; United Fruit; Gillette; J.C. Penney; Texas Company; Nestle Hair Waving; Glyco-Thymoline; Agfa; Campfire; United Fruit; DuPont; Campbell's Soup; William Esty on Production Group and high-brow vs. low-brow advertising; tabloid advertising
    - 1927 Sept. 13 (Box 1)
      Simmons Mattresses; newspaper advertising
    - 1927 Sept. 20 (Box 1)
      No notes were taken
    - 1927 Sept. 27 (Box 1)
      New business solicitations; JWT billings; Gantner & Mattern; Walker Dishwasher Corporation; Nestle Hair Waving; Cliquot; Texas Company; DuPont; Campbell Soup; American Bemberg Corporation; Scientific American; Royal Baking; Hooven; Pennsylvania Railroad; John Reber; Chicago Office; London Office; testimonial advertising
    - 1927 Oct. 4, Dec. 6; Dec. 13 (Box 1)
    - 1927 Oct. 11 (Box 1)
      Maxwell House Coffee; Cutex; General Motors; Buston; Gruen; Chesebrough; Woodbury; Phenix Cheese; Fleischmann; Royal Baking Powder; Simmons; foreign advertising; San Francisco Office; London Office; Europe
    - 1927 Oct. 18 (Box 1)
      Pennsylvania Rubber; Corning Glass; Pyrex; Mrs. Watson's Pie Crust; William Palmer
    - 1927 Oct. 25 (Box 1)
      Piggly Wiggly; Sterling Remedies; Nestle Hair Waving; United Fruit; Simmons; Gulbransen Piano Company; Federal Radio; W.F. Lochridge (JWT Chicago); conflicts of interest
    - 1927 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
      Sales summary; Muffets; Scott Paper; Saturday Evening Post; Paul Cherington; James Young (JWT Chicago); AAAA meeting; accountancy; American Newspaper Publishers Association; newspaper vs. magazine advertising; agency percentage commission system
    - 1927 Nov. 10 (Box 1)
      Sales summary; Scott Paper; Saturday Evening Post; Paul Cherington; newspaper vs. magazine advertising
    - 1927 Nov. 15 (Box 1)
      Soap advertising; Lifebuoy; William Esty
    - 1927 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
      Gruen Watch Company; Pentagon watches; jewelry advertising; Bill Groom
    - 1927 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
      Newspaper advertising; White Plains newspaper investigation
    - 1927 Dec. 20 (Box 1)
      Foreign Advertising; Piggly Wiggly; Royal Baking Powder; Lux; General Motors; Dominion Rubber; Gruen; Canada; Samuel Meek; Howard Henderson (Cincinnati Office); Hooven & Allison
    - 1927 Dec. 29 (Box 1)
      Globe-Wernicke; N. W. Ayer; Northern Warren; Pinaud; Maxwell House; Cutex Polish; Unguentine; discussion of creating something like N.W. Ayer's "Plan Board"; account losses; drug stores
    - 1928 Jan. 5 (Box 1)
      Population figures; demographics; grocery stores; retail shopping areas; Paul Cherington
    - 1928 Jan. 12, Apr. 25 (Box 1)
      No notes were taken; letter from W.F. Lochridge (JWT Chicago) on weekly staff meetings
    - 1928 Jan. 17 (Box 1)
      Retail shopping; Simmons; Martex; Dodge; Retail Shopping Areas book; Paul Cherington
    - 1928 Jan. 24 (Box 1)
      Simmons Company; George Fowler
    - 1928 Jan. 31 (Box 1)
      Marketing art; Edward J. Steichen; photography; color photographs; photography for newspaper reproduction; models vs. society women
    - 1928 Feb. 7 (Box 1)
      Newspaper advertising; tabloid vs. "class" magazine advertising; Fleischmann; Pyrex
    - 1928 Feb. 16 (Box 1)
      Newspaper advertising; Hellman's; Cutex; Cashmere Bouquet; General Motors; Macy; Maxwell House Coffee; B.F. Goodrich; Ipana; Associated Savings Bank; Berlin; print jobbers; indirect advertising; train cards; radio advertising and broadcasting
    - 1928 Feb. 21 (Box 1)
      Ford Motors; Barrelled Sunlight; Royal Baking Powder; Mississippi Valley; Fleischmann; Harvard Bok Award for research work in advertising
    - 1928 Feb. 28 (Box 1)
      Maxwell House Coffee; Lux Toilet Soap; Palmolive; Fleischmann; Keds; Atwater Kent; magazine circulation; testimonials; international advertising; Canada; media research; readership and family income
    - 1928 Mar. 6 (Box 1)
      Lux Toilet Soap; Woolworth; Phenix; Hellmann; Pyrex; John Ward Shoes; Pennsylvania Railroad; Nemo Corsets; newspaper advertising
    - 1928 Mar. 15 (Box 1)
      General Motors; Cutex; Van Camp; Simmons; Certo; Canadian market; Richmond Watson; timeline of Chevrolet from Berlin Office
    - 1928 Mar. 20 (Box 1)
      Maxwell House Coffee; Yuban; Wrigley Chewing Gum; Colgate; Lever Brothers; Super Suds; Canada Dry; newspaper advertising; coffee market
    - 1928 Mar. 27 (Box 1)
      Macy's; Simmons Beds; J. C. Penney; retail drug stores and chains; "Newspaper Cooperation"
    - 1928 Apr. 4 (Box 1)
      J. C. Penney's; LaSalle; Buick; General Motors; Gorman; Chevrolet (Germany); Libby; automobile advertising; JWT London; international advertising
    - 1928 Apr. 9 (Box 1)
      Pond's; Simmons; Lux; Fleischmann; Red Cap; Keds; Woodbury; Pond's; Carter's; Rinso; Ford; display advertising; editorial advertising; history of advertising; magazine advertising; moving picture advertising; testimonials; celebrity endorsements; Hollywood; men in advertisements; fashion
    - 1928 Apr. 18 (Box 1)
      Barrelled Sunlight; J. C. Penney's; Curtis Publishing; newspaper advertising
    - 1928 May 3 (Box 1)
      Test campaigns; Bovril; Pebeco; Pinaud; Pond's; Aunt Jemina; Campbell's Soup; Pond's; Lux Toilet Soap; J.C. Penney; health claims of products; advertising demonstrations; Great Britain; Canada
    - 1928 May 9 (Box 1)
      Fleischmann; Scott Paper; B.F. Goodrich; store displays; test campaigns; newspaper advertising; outdoor advertising
    - 1928 May 16 (Box 1)
      Stuebing Cowan Company; Pennsylvania Railroad Company; U.S. Rubber Keds; Pennsylvania Rubber; Graybar Electric Company; Goodrich; Maxwell House; resigning accounts to acquire another; Radio Department
    - 1928 May 23 (Box 1)
      Woolworth's; Phenix Cheese; Kroger Stores; Penick & Ford; Standard Oil Company; Interstate Commerce Commission; Miller Rubber Company; Fleischmann; advertising costs and scale
    - 1928 June 1 (Box 1)
      Norwich Pharmacal; Amolin; Odorono; Society for Electrical Development; Postum; Certo; Maxwell House; Certo Corporation; cosmetics advertising; radio advertising
    - 1928 June 6 (Box 1)
      Borvil; Savora; A & P; Colman; Krumm; Scott Paper; Flako Pie Crust; Lumber Association; Cotton Textile Institute; test campaigns; packaging; newspaper advertising
    - 1928 June 13 (Box 1)
      Outdoor advertising; Clyde S. Thompson
    - 1928 June 20 (Box 1)
      Outdoor advertising; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company; Camel Cigarettes; Atwater Kent Radio; Maxwell House; Jantzen; Dodge; advertising copy
    - 1928 June 27 (Box 1)
      General Motors; South American advertising; William Ricketts
    - 1928 July 6 (Box 1)
      General Motors; Chevrolet; Coca-Cola; Wrigley; Times Square; outdoor advertising; tobacco advertising; electric signs and spectaculars; street car advertising; posters vs. painted displays
    - 1928 July 11 (Box 1)
      Cheek Neal; Goodrich; chain store sales; radio advertising; radio broadcast networks; short wave
    - 1928 July 18 (Box 1)
      Fleischmann; Liberty Company; nutritional yeast research
    - 1928 July 25 (Box 1)
      Department of Commerce; Census of 1930; automobile advertising; distribution research
    - 1928 Aug. 1 (Box 1)
      Telephone Company; yeast research; Bovril; telephone sales; toll calls; telephone directories; testimonials
    - 1928 Aug. 8 (Box 1)
      General Motors; U.S. Steel; Pennsylvania Railroad; Shell Oil; Woolworth; Cream of Wheat; new accounts; international offices; John Reber; Sam Meek
    - 1928 Aug. 17 (Box 1)
      Palmolive; Colgate; Royal Gelatin; Certo; Mount Vernon Ladies' Association; Society for Electrical Development; Vogue; magazine advertising; women's magazines
    - 1928 Aug. 22 (Box 1)
      American Association of Advertising Agencies; Curtis Publishing Company; magazine duplication research; magazine advertising; Daniel Starch
    - 1928 Aug. 29 (Box 1)
      National Lumber Manufacturing Association; Curtis Publishing Company; Florida Citrus Growers Exchange; Pennsylvania Railroad; Mavis; Stetson; Celanese; Woolworth; trade paper advertising; service departments
    - 1928 Sept. 12 (Box 1)
      Royal Baking Powder; Postum; Pyrex; Pebeco; Libby; advertising estimates; coupons
    - 1928 Sept. 19 (Box 2)
      Lux Toilet Soap; Fleischmann; advertising drawings; photographs; coupons
    - 1928 Sept. 26 (Box 2)
      Florida Citrus Exchange; Royal Baking Powder; new business solicitation; coupons
    - 1928 Oct. 3 (Box 2)
      Woodbury's Facial Soap; Straus; Sterno; soft drinks; Coca-Cola; Moxie; Caffeine and the US Supreme Court; General Motors; Cadillac; Port Elizabeth; South Africa; coupons; Gilbert Kinney; John U. Reber; Stewart L. Mims
    - 1928 Oct. 17 (Box 2)
      American Association of Advertising Agencies; chain stores; Phenix Cheese; Kraft Cheese; American Stores; Del Monte; coupons
    - 1928 Oct. 24 (Box 2)
      Coupons; National Cooperative Sales Service; Vick's Vapo Rub; Scott Paper; Welch's Grape Juice; Curtis Publishing; Gorham; new business
    - 1928 Oct. 31 (Box 2)
      Goodrich Company; tire advertising; William G. Palmer; Kennett Hinks; San Francisco Office
    - 1928 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
      Simmons Company; Macy's; George Fowler
    - 1928 Nov. 21 (Box 2)
      Gorham Plateware; Union Tpbacco; Herbert Tareyton; International Telephone and Telegraph; Shell Oil; Kraft Company; Phenix; Toledo Scale; New England Council; General Motors; John U. Reber
    - 1928 Nov. 28 (Box 2)
      Fleischmann; Stox; Yeast; Vegex; store displays
    - 1928 Dec. 13 (Box 2)
      London Office; Lux Toilet Soap; General Motors; Lucky Strike; candy; Europe
    - 1928 Dec. 19 (Box 2)
      Industrial Sales Conference of the Electrical Industry; electrical products; Edison; William L. Day
    - 1928 Dec. 27 (Box 2)
      Newspaper advertising; Pennsylvania Railroad; railway posters in England; Stewart L. Mims; Clyde Thompson
    - 1929 Jan. 4 (Box 2)
      Goodrich Company; Hellman's; Martex; Simmons; Lord & Thomas; pricing in chain stores; business outlook for 1929; Alexandria Office; Rumania
    - 1929 Jan. 9 (Box 2)
      Maxwell House Coffee; Lux Toilet Soap; cigarette advertising; Tareyton; Camel; Chesterfield; Union Tobacco Company; William C. Esty
    - 1929 Jan. 16 (Box 2)
      International Telephone and Telegraph; Postal Company; All America Cables; Curtiss Aeroplane & Motor Company; National Diary Products Corporation; John U. Reber
    - 1929 Jan. 23 (Box 2)
      J. C. Penney Company; Poster Advertising; outdoor advertising; buying power; Clyde S. Thompson
    - 1929 Jan. 30 (Box 2)
      New business; Curtiss Aeroplane & Motors Company; Sheffield Farms Company; Electrical Development; Boston Edison; publicity; Warsaw Office; John U. Reber; Edward Fuller
    - 1929 Feb. 13 (Box 2)
      Foreign office development; Royal Baking Powder; Scott Paper; Cutex Manicure Sets; General Motors; McGraw-Hill; Media Department; South Africa; Gilbert Kinney [no minutes recorded Feb. 7, Feb. 20, Apr. 24, 1929]
    - 1929 Feb. 27 (Box 2)
      New accounts; general business outlook; outdoor advertising; American Tobacco Company; General Motors; Stanley Resor
    - 1929 Mar. 6 (Box 2)
      J. W. Thompson reputation; client satisfaction; publication representatives; John U. Reber
    - 1929 Mar. 13 (Box 2)
      Royal Baking Powder; magazine circulation figures
    - 1929 Mar. 20 (Box 2)
      Industrial film business; motion pictures; filmmakers; YMCA Motion Picture Bureau; sound pictures; film production costs; distribution; home projection
    - 1929 Mar. 28 (Box 2)
      Testimonial advertising; Stanley Resor
    - 1929 Apr. 3 (Box 2)
      Radio advertising; Maxwell House Coffee; Aunt Jemima; Lucky Strike; General Motors; sponsored programming
    - 1929 Apr. 10 (Box 2)
      Radio advertising; National Broadcasting Company; Radio Homemaker's Club; Royal Baking Powder; outdoor advertising; psychology of advertising
    - 1929 Apr. 17 (Box 2)
      Industrial Alcohol Institute; denatured alcohol; antifreeze; Prestone; William G. Palmer
    - 1929 May 1 (Box 2)
      American Association of Advertising Agencies; Cream of Wheat; Irving Trust; Lloyd Baillie
    - 1929 May 7 (Box 2)
      Contemporary art; international advertising; history of JWT's international offices; General Motors; James Webb Young; Sam Meeks
    - 1929 May 14 (Box 2)
      New business; Curtiss Aeroplane and Motor Company; DuPont; Atlantic Coast Fisheries; New England Refining Company; Lever Brothers; yeast; mail order advertising; advertising readership; circulation; testimonials; coupons; Lux Toilet Soap; Cutex; John U. Reber; William Esty
    - 1929 May 21 (Box 2)
      Hexylresorcinols; Sharp & Dohme; Unguentine; Hexadent; medical claims in advertising; John B. Watson
    - 1929 May 28 (Box 2)
      Window display advertising; Pennsylvania Railroad; Irving Trust Company; silver fleet; William L. Day
    - 1929 June 4 (Box 2)